Theme of home is something that’s of universal application.
关于家的话题是全人类共同的诉求
It’s a common saying or understanding
众所皆知
that everyone is searching for their home.
每个人都在寻找家
We even have one book published called ‘Home Comfort’.
我们还出版了一本书叫做《家的安慰》
[Age of Search for Reality the Beautiful]
寻找真实与美的时代
But home … you can say ‘home’ implies
谈到家，你可以将它理解为
family, loving affectionate relationships.
家庭，充满关爱的情感关系
But for that to be something real and substantial,
但要找到更真实和本质的家和爱
and not stereotypical, then it‘ll have to begin
不是常规化那种
The perennial questions: “Who am I?
那个永恒的问题：“我是谁？
Where’ve I come from? What is my purpose?”
来自哪儿？我的人生目标是什么？”
So, when you think about search, like, this is the age of search.
说到寻找，这是一个寻找的时代，对吗？
We have Google.
我们有Google
Search—this whole age is predominated by search.
搜索—整个时代 就被 搜索主导
Social networking— people are searching.
社交网络—人们都在搜索和寻找
They’re searching for their counterparts.
寻找同伴
We’re searching … What are we searching for?
我们寻找...寻找什么？
Besides the objective things like how to acquire
除了怎样买到物美价廉的客观物品
That’s one idea. That’s good idea.
这是一种想法，挺好的
But what are we really searching for?
但我们真正在寻找什么？
What’s driving us to consume?
那些驱使我们消费的是什么？
What’s driving consumption is the search for fulfillment.
寻找满足是消费的驱动力
So, how will we find fulfillment,
因此，如何找到满足
if in fact we are the subjective aspect—
事实上，我们的确是主观的意识存在
conscious living beings, embodied,
有觉知的生命体
navigating the objective existence. Subjects navigating the objective world.
在客观世界里航行，主体在客观世界里航行
We have mistakenly bought into the notion
我们错误的被赋予一个概念
that through the acquisition …
通过获取
to acquire, control and consume …
通过取得，控制和消费
Through acquisition and consumption that we’ll find fulfillment.
通过获得和消费，我们能找到满足
But that means for the soul, subject,
但那意味着，灵魂，主体
to try and acquire, control and consume objects—
去尝试获取控制和消费物质
What is the soul is searching for is sweetness, love, affection.
灵魂真正的寻找的是甜美，爱和情感
Sometimes it mistakenly thinks that “I’ll achieve that
有时我们错误的以为自己可以
through consumption, acquisition, acquiring
通过尽可能多地消费和掠获
as much of the objective world as possible,
这个客观的世界里的物体
and then I’ll find fulfillment.”
就越得到满足
Just like I’ve mentioned many times:
就像我曾多次提到
through the Internet, social networking,
那些互联网和社交网络
there’re also sites you have like matchmaker.com—
还有很多婚配网站
You smile! [Laughing]
笑了吧
Where the idea is: “Hey!
这些网站的想法是：“嗨！运用互联网的威力
Everyone is searching for their counterpart.
每个人都在寻找自己的另一半
What better way then this! The maximum amount of data.
还有比这更棒的主意嘛！这里有如此庞大的数据库
Like, if we share all the information that’s known about us
如果我们分享自己所有的信息
and put that in a giant database
将它汇集到数据库里
then there’ll be someone on the other side—
那头有另外一些人也在填写理想标准
Like the old song,
就像老歌唱的
“Matchmaker, matchmaker, make me a match,
红娘，红娘，为我撮合姻缘
find me a find, catch me a catch.”
找个好郎君，觅个好姑娘
Through search, through the Internet.
通过搜索，通过网络
It sounds like a good idea, it sounds tenable.
听起来不错，貌似成立
Fill in a form, put all my ideal criteria
填一张表，写满我的理想标准
and then find the match in the database.
然后在数据库里寻找一个配对对象
But then it comes again back to
但接下来回到
what is our conception of self.
我们自身的问题
Who are we and what are we substantially?
我们是谁？本质是什么？
So, if we approach it from an exclusively scientific point of view,
如果从科学的角度来看
then we may conclude that we’re carbon–based life forms.
总结为碳基的生命形式
But I can’t imagine someone phrasing their search criteria as:
但很难想象有人会把自己的理想条件写成：
“Carbon–based life form seeks intimate relationship
碳基生命形式想和另一个碳基生命形式
with other carbon–based life form.”
建立亲密关系
Sounds a little … it doesn’t sound too romantic or appealing.
听起来有点...不好听也不太浪漫
This seems something less than the dignity of the human race.
有失人类体面
And less than a full realisation of our potential.
也完全没有意识到我们的潜能
So, the ideal, the search criteria we place,
因此，我们输入了那个理想型
no matter who we try to impose this counterpart upon,
无论我们将这个理想的另一半加到谁身上
the soulmate,
无论谁是那个灵魂伴侣
inevitably they disappoint being less than ideal,
必将因为达不到意中人的标准而让我们失望
inevitably it becomes frustrated and enters … dissolves, dissolution.
肯定会遭受挫折，一切理想都会瓦解，消散
Because no one other than the Absolute can reciprocate ideal criteria.
因为只有那位绝对神者符合那个理想标准
Ideal here is synonymous with the Absolute.
完美的意中人是绝对真理的代名词
So, indirectly what all this search is about—
因此，这所有的追寻都间接的指向
it’s the search for Śrī Kṛṣṇa— Reality the Beautiful.
寻找圣奎师那，那个美丽的本真